Steven Hocking

46 Longford Road, Reddish, Stockport, SK5 6UX.

0750 345 6222 steve@codemunki.es

http://www.codemunki.es/ http://stackoverflow.com/story/stevehocking https://github.com/steve-codemunkies

Profile

I am a passionate, highly engaged technical architect/principal software engineer, with a focus on delivering high quality software first time, every time. I have extensive experience working in organisations of differing size and maturity in their experience of delivering software.

My team are currently working to replace the aged Beds system for the following reasons:

- Current system is nearly twenty years old, and is extremely difficult to maintain
- Current system is not designed for the workload being processed
- Current system is unable to support current or future business requirements

I have been working with my team to re-implement the system as a set of discrete micro-services, making use of client-server and event-bus architectures as appropriate.

My leadership style is to facilitate the members of my team in solving the issues placed before them, whilst providing technical guidance. I feel that success is best achieved by engaging every member of a team, and the best way to do this is to show, not tell.

Technical Experience

- C# / .NET Framework 14 Years
- Microsoft SQL Server 19 Years
- ASP.NET MVC 7 Years
- Test Driven Development 7 Years
- WCF Services 5 Years
- Modern JavaScript (Durandal/Angular/Karma/Jasmine) 3 Years
- .NET Core 24 Months
- SQL Server/Windows Server Maintenance 30 Months
- Continuous Integration (Jenkins) and Automated Deployment (Octopus) 30 Months
- PowerShell 5 Years
- NoSQL (MongoDb) 24 Months
- RabbitMq 45 Months
- TopShelf (windows services) 45 months

Technical Architecture Experience

• On the Beach 2015-Onwards

Team Management Experience

- On The Beach 2015-Onwards initially 3 developers, currently 2 senior software engineers, 3 software engineers, 2 junior software engineers, 1 quality assurance engineer (automated testing), 1 business analyst, 1 product owner
- Swinton 2012-2013 4 developers and one tester
- Intechnica 2010-2011 initially 2 developers and one tester, finally 4 developers and one tester
- PwC 2007-2010 multiple teams, from 2 developer-5 developers, also including testers and business analysts

Work History

- On The Beach Group plc, Cheadle Senior .NET Developer/Team Lead Principal Software Engineer (.NET) (Lead) – January 2016-Present
 - I have worked with the Talent team to grow the team from 3 developers (2+me) to 1 Principal (me), 2 Senior Software Engineers, 3 Software Engineers, 2 Junior Software Engineers, 1 QA/Automation Tester, 1 Business Analyst and 1 Product Owner
 - My team is responsible for the Beds system (used to manage room bookings and contracts)
 and the Transfers system (used to manage airport transfer bookings and contracts)
 - Between them these systems process bookings covering ~70% of the business revenues
 - o I have helped move the team from infrequent deliveries of medium size with moderate quality to frequent deliveries of small, high quality changes; this has been achieved by:
 - using TDD, CI (Jenkins) and Automated Deployments (Octopus Deployment)
 - additionally my team DevOps the systems the applications run on
 - I have architected and directed the creation of new tools to allow users to self-manage systems without development intervention
 - The Beds and Transfers systems are both Webforms applications, and my team are enhancing these applications using a number of technologies:
 - WCF to build high performance/high availability core services
 - ASP.NET Core MVC/WebApi along with React.is to build management applications
 - TopShelf (with Quartz.net and/or RabbitMq) to provide background processing services
- On The Beach Group plc, Cheadle .NET Developer October 2015-January 2016
 - o I was employed by On The Beach to help raise the technical standard of the .NET team
 - Promoted to the position of Senior .NET Developer/Team Leader
- Sabbatical (following birth of second child) June 2015-October 2015
- Havas Health Software, Manchester Contract Software Engineer April 2014-June 2015 (renewed three times)
 - Contracted as a Software Engineer for my experience with .NET, understanding of TDD and SOLID principals, and ability to reliably deliver required changes.
- Ukash/Smart Voucher Ltd, Bollington, Cheshire Contract Developer March 2013-March 2014 (renewed twice)
 - The IT director wished to improve the way his development team worked so I was contracted as a Developer for my experience with .NET, understanding of TDD and SOLID principals and the mentoring work I had previously done.
- Swinton Insurance Ltd, Manchester November 2011-March 2013
 - Delivered Optima service used to adjust pricing, designed to be able to process 600,000 requests per day/420 requests per minute in approximately 500ms per request
 - Delivered a refactor of an existing service (CPS) to provide better MI to the business
- Intechnica LLP, Manchester October 2010-November 2011
- 2Ergo Ltd, Salford Quays June 2010-September 2010
- PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC) LLP, UK IT Design and Build (D&B), Manchester July 2004-June 2010
- Radius Computer Services Ltd, Altrincham September 1998-July 2004

Education

- Technical Specialist: Web Applications Development with Microsoft .NET Framework 4 (70-515) May 2011
- Microsoft Certified Application Developer June 2004
 Transcript viewable at https://mcp.microsoft.com/authenticate/validatemcp.aspx (Transcript ID: 663027; Access code: 1976Sh0804).
- University of Central Lancashire BSc Software Engineering (Hons) 2:II July 1998
- University of Central Lancashire HND Software Engineering July 1996